你有没看上这里的谁？
You got your eye on anyone?
嗯，还没
Em, not really.
其实刚才我在跟老鼠说话
Actually, I was talking to the mouse.
既然提到这一点
这里有几个女人长得还真是火辣
But now you mention it,
some of those women are pretty hot,
我们刚把她们从幽灵那里救出来
在他们还没发现我们不是很酷之前
我们得好好利用这一点
and we did just save them from the Wraith,
and we gotta trade on that while we can,
before they discover that we're not that cool.
坐下  我准备好
Sit down, I'm ready.
现在你仍然十分热情地当志愿者
令我感到惊奇
I'm surprised you're still eager to volunteer for this Rodney.
你也是知道的
我一向乐于助人
Well you know me. Always eager to help.
好的  你对这个过程有什么疑问的？
怎么说你也是个科学家
Right. So do you have any questions about the process?
I mean you are a scientist.
呃  恕我冒昧  医学不单是门科学
而且也有些巫术的成分？
Uh, yeah. I'm sorry, medicine is about as much of a science as,
I don't know, voodoo?
我感兴趣的是  这样我就可以像Sheppard少校和你一样
使用古代的科学技术了
All I need to know is that, that will enable me to use Ancient technology,
like Major Sheppard or yourself.
也许吧  你是第一个临床实验者
Yes, hopefully. You are the first human trial.
那为什么不现在？
Well why now?
我是说  如果可能的话  我们需要
尽可能多的人类基因
I mean, if it's possible,
we need as many people with the gene, as we could get.
事实上  没有食品药物管理署的批准
我们不可能在地球上……
Well actually, without proper FDA approval,
virtually impossible on Earth to...
这么说吧  在这飞马星系
这么做是合法的
Let's just say, it's legal here, in the Pegasus Galaxy.
并且十分安全的
And completely safe.
我只是在目前基因治疗技术的水平下
对你的DNA进行操作  开始吧
As far as experimental gene therapy goes.
I am manipulating your DNA. Here we go.
等等  也许你该解释得清楚些
Maybe you should tell me more.
我们认为ATA  也就是古代科技激活
是由一个始终在起作用的基因造成的
We believe ATA, or Ancient Technology Activation,
is caused by a single gene that's always on.
它指导身体各个部位的细胞
产生一系列的蛋白质和酶
Instructing various cells of the body
to produce a series of proteins and enzymes,
并与皮肤  神经系统  大脑
互相影响
that interact with the skin,
the nervous system, and the brain.
我将通过注射鼠类逆转录病毒
为你的细胞添加遗失的基因
In this case we're using a mouse retro virus
to deliver the missing gene to your cells.
鼠类逆转录病毒？
A mouse retro virus
已经被抑制了的
It's been de-activated.
有什么副作用吗？
Well are there any side effects?
嘴唇干燥  头疼
不可抑止的向轮子冲过去的冲动
Dry mouth, headache,
the irresistable urge to run on a small wheel.
还真有趣  什么时候会生效？
Oh that's very amusing. So how long till it starts working?
需要一些时间  那是什么
It could take some time. What is that?
这是我在一个实验室里找到的
是一个古代人用来做实验的东西
It's something I found in one of the research labs.
Something the Ancients were experimenting with.
你知道这是什么吗？
Do you know what it is?
当然
Pretty sure.
我们可以将海水淡化  存在大的储水槽里
城市的供水就能解决了
Desalinizing the sea water and storing it in
tanks big enough to supply the whole city.
好啊  那淡水问题就不存在了
Good. So fresh water, won't be a problem.
现在看来有些古代科技需要使用者
携带那些基因
It seems some Ancient technology requires
the user to have the gene.
其他的只需要初始化一下
一旦被激活  就像控制室一样
Other things merely require initialisation.
Once activated, like the control room.
任何人都可以通过按钮使它工作
Anyone can push the buttons to make them work.
早晨好  Weir博士
Good morning Doctor Weir.
早晨好  小心点！
我觉得我们需要划出专门的休闲区域了
Morning. Careful!
I think we need to designate some recreational areas.
是啊
Yes.
我们必须把走廊清理一下
尽快把东西都放好
We certainly need to clear the hallway
and have everything put away as soon as possible.
那些万年古植物会有位置吗？
And can we lose the ten thousand year old dead plants?
当然  我们仍然在给大家分配居住区
Of course. We're still in the process of making
sure everyone's been assigned living quarters.
Sheppard少校正花时间来腾出空间来
Major Sheppard seems to be taking his time locating enough space.
这次探险的安全问题…………
Well the safety and security of this expedition...
好了  我准备好了
Ok, I'm ready!
我的天啊
Oh my God!
你看见了吗？
Did you see that?
看见了  你们……
Yes! what that...
我没事
I'm fine.
看  Becketts的基因治疗成功了
Look, Becketts gene therapy worked!
我可以激活它
这简直就是个金钟罩
I was able to activate this.
It's a personal shield, that acts like a protective skin.
而且这有减少惯性的能力
因为我一点感觉也没有  看着
They must have inertia dampening properties too
because I didn't feel a thing. Watch this.
打我
Hit me.
嗷！天啊！
Ow! God!
你没必要出这么重的拳
我注意到他一点也没犹豫
You didn't have to swing so hard.
And I notice that he didn't even hesitate.
我仍然不能理解  你为什么要让人把你
从阳台上扔下来作为测试
I'm still trying to understand,
how you thought it was a good idea to test this device,
by having someone throw you off a balcony.
信不信由你
刚才那个不是第一次了
Oh believe me.
That's not the first time we tried it.
我对他开枪…………
I shot him.....
是腿！
In the leg!
我刀枪不入了
I'm invulnerable.
你以前不是一直鼓吹科学实验要
恰当而安全的一步步进行么？
Aren't you the one who's always spouting off about
how proper and careful scientific procedure must be adhered to?
刀枪不入
Invulnerable.
好吧  不说这个了
我们去开会吧
Alright, take it off. Let's go have this meeting.
她是在嫉妒我
She's jealous.
是啊  脸都绿了
Oh yes, green with envy.
有问题  我自己都进不去
This could be a problem. I can't get at it.
只是试一试
Just checking.
第三集：捉迷藏
Episode 3 : HIDE AND SEEK
常胜将军怎么样
I'm thinking Mr Invincible.
不可触摸的船长
Captain Untouchable.
哇  这不错
Ooh, that's good.
你们好了吗？
You guys done?
我已经为这个基因治疗忙了好几个月了
请原谅我现在有些激动  因为第一个临床实验成功了
I've been working on this gene therapy for months,
forgive me for wanting to celebrate the fact that it worked,
on the first human trial.
那我们开始狂欢吧
Oh, let's all have a toast.
随便说说  你在做完手术后
有没吃过东西？
Just a thought here, but have you tried eating
or drinking anything since you put that on?
太好了
That's great.
这比我猜想的还要严重
This may be more serious than I suspected.
哦  谢谢  我现在饿了
我该怎么办？
Oh thankyou. I'm hungry already. What am I going to do?
如果我不把这东西取下来
今天我就会饿死
If I don't get this stupid thing off, I'll be dead by the end of the day.
放松  人没有水可以活3，4天
Relax. You can live three or four days without water.
我是说吃的
I'm talking about food.
你读过一些关于这个设备的文献
上面说应该怎么把它取下来？
You found some Ancient text with the device.
What did it say about taking it off?
没错  是有详细的说明
但我全都跳过了
Oh yeah, there were some explicit instructions,
which I chose to completely ignore.
一些古代科技可使用
心理方面的东西进行控制
Well, some Ancient technology uses
a mental component for operation.
闭嘴  我在想东西
Just shut up, I'm thinking.
有没可能基因治疗的效果不是永久的？
Is there any chance that
the gene therapy isn't permanent?
可能
It's possible.
我死定了
Oh, I'm a dead man.
以现有的人力资源
我们应该可以保持这一地区的安全
We can probably maintain security in this area,
with the limited number of personnel we have.
我们可以帮忙
My people can help.
谢谢  Teyla  这一次我们会
考虑Ethosian人其他可以帮忙的方式
Thankyou Teyla. For the time being
we'll find other way's that the Ethosians can contribute.
你们不相信我们？
You do not trust us?
不是这样的  是因为我们需要时间
来训练你们  以熟悉我们的武器和战术
It's not that, it's just that we, we need to train
your people in our weapons and tactics.
是你请我加入你们这个团队的
You invited me to be a member of your team.
我们也尊重你们的知识和专长
And we value your knowledge and expertise.
就像我们尊重所有Ethosian人一样
As we value all the Ethosians.
现在看来  规划好的区域足够
给每个人分配生活的空间
For now, there should be more than enough living space for everyone,
within the designated area.
我们总是生活在幽灵的阴影之下
We have always lived in the shadow of the Wraith
但我们还从没在这样的地方呆过
But my people have never been in a place such as this.
他们有些恐慌  甚至怀疑
这里有鬼魂的存在
They are afraid. Some believe that
the ghosts of the ancestors remain.
我认为这不是问题  我们还需要一些时间
来了解整个城市的情况
I don't think that's the case, but still we're gonna need
a bit more time in order to explore the entire city.
我们是小心翼翼的星际宇航员
We're very cautious, intergalactic, explorers.
我们不希望再有人像Hollan那样
受到伤害
And we don't want anyone else getting hurt,
the way Hollan did.
每个人都必须知道如果不是确定的话
就不要动陌生的东西
I mean everyone needs to understand they're not to touch
anything unfamiliar, unless it's been cleared first.
这一点很重要
你不知道  就算是平淡无味的东西都可能致命
It's very important.
You never know, even a tiny little innocuous thing, can kill you.
就当死人说话好了
Dead man talking.
Carson
Carson.
Weir博士
Doctor Weir.
Groden已经带了一支队伍检查了
古代研究资料里有关那个保护层的内容
So Groden's got a team, going through the Ancients research
material that accompanied the shield device.
McKay已经都读过那些了  他没有发现有用的东西
他可是这儿最聪明的人了
But McKay's been through it, and he didn't find anything helpful.
And he is the smartest guy here.
他总是这么说自己  听着
我感觉糟透了  这可能是人工把基因强行加入的恶果
So he likes to tell us. Listen, I feel terrible.
It's possible this is the result of artificially imposing the gene.
我有另一个想法  我们知道
有一个心理的方法可以使用古代科技
Well I have another theory.
We know that there is a mental component,
to using Ancient technology.
不需要你来提醒我  这是我亲自经历的
连同那个嗡嗡作响的武器一起回到地球的
You don't have to remind me.
I experienced it first hand, with that drone weapon, back on Earth.
是啊  你不认为McKay有可能
可以用他的意念来去除那个东西？
Exactly. So don't you think it stands to reason
that McKay should be able to shut this thing off with his mind?
你是说他并不想去掉那个东西？
Are you suggesting he doesn't want to shut it off?
我们也许可以在这里定居下来
但这个地方  还是缺乏安全感
We may be settling in here, but this place,
it's still pretty intimidating.
一个巨大的被废弃的城市  充满了我们无法理解的东西
还感受着幽灵无处不在的威胁
A giant abandoned city,
full of things way beyond our level of understanding.
Impending threat of attack from the Wraith.
不对  这里一到夜里就十分恐怖
No question, it gets bloody creepy here at night.
我并不是说这是有意的
也许是无意的
So I'm not saying it's conscious,
but perhaps subconsciously.
我想他并不想脱水而死
I don't think he wants to die of dehydration.
我也不想啊  但他还没到那种程度
No, neither do I. But he's not there yet.
难道你认为到了那一步的时候
那个东西会自己关闭吗？
You think when it comes down to it,
the shield will just shut itself down?
古代人已经足够聪明了
他们一定做了事故保障装置
The Ancients were smart enough to put failsafe's into their other technology.
当危难迫近时  这整个城市从深海中浮了起来
This entire city rose from the deep of the ocean,
when danger was imminent.
他们为什么要设计一个
可以置人于死地的防护层呢？
Why would they design a personal shield
that could kill you?
我也宁愿相信你是对的
看在Rodney的份上
I certainly hope you're right. For Rodney's sake.
自毁系统需要两套密码
The self destruct system requires two separate codes.
两套密码是独一无二的
这里的每一个人都必须记住自己的密码
Now each code is unique,
and everyone here will be required to memorise their code.
不用给我了  对不起
Well don't bother giving me one. Sorry.
从目前掌握的情况看  这是飞马星座上唯一
可以与地球通信的星际门
As far as we know, this is the only Stargate in the Pegasus galaxy,
which is capable of dialling Earth.
这使它成为抵御幽灵的最后一道防线
Which would make it the last line of defence
against the Wraith.
如果他们开始攻击  这对我们来说是个巨大的威胁
我们坚决不能让他们控制这套房子
If they're gonna attack, which we must consider a very real threat.
We simply cannot let them gain control of this complex.
如果两套密码都被正确输入的话
发生器将会超载  这个过程有30秒
If both codes are properly entered,
the naquadah generator will overload. It will take 30 seconds.
你确定威力够大吗？
You're sure it'll do enough damage?
见过20千吨当量的核爆炸吗？
Ever see a 20 kiloton nuclear explosion?
我……其实没有那么大
我想我们该告诉Teyla我们现在的进度
I have....Not up close.
Look, I think we should tell Teyla what's going on here.
直到现在  我们都还不知道是不是其中一个
Ethosian人泄露了你去那个星球的消息
At this moment, we still don't know if it was one of the Ethosians,
who tipped off your arrival to their planet.
我相信Teyla
I trust Teyla.
我也是  但是Teyla相信她的人民
如果我们告诉她  她会告诉她的人民
我觉得我们还需要时间去加深对他们的了解
So do I, but Teyla trusts her people. If we tell her,
she'll wanna tell them, and I need more time to get to know them.
他们以为他死了
但就在他们转身要走的刹那
Well, they thought he was finally dead.
But when they turned their backs to go....
冰球面具下那双冰冷的眼睛睁开了
他提着血淋淋的刀站了起来！
His cold dead eyes opened beneath his hockey mask, and he rose up with his giant bloody knife!
冰球面具是什么？
What's a hockey mask?
冰球是一种比赛
运动员们在冰上滑动  努力把球送到网里
Hockey's a game.
Guys skate around the ice and try to put a puck into the net?
守门员要戴面具  它很…………
The goalie's wear masks, it's really....
……吓人
....scary
再说点冰球的东西
Tell us more of this game.
我们可以玩吗？
Can we play it?
事实上  我不觉得冰球有趣
橄榄球  橄榄球才是男人的运动
我们下次再说橄榄球
Actually, I don't really see the attraction.
Now football, football's a real mans sport,
but we'll save that for another time.
好了  睡觉时间到了
Yes, it's time for bed
记住  孩子们  明晚
我给你们讲榆木大街的恶梦
And remember, tomorrow night kids,
another tale called, Nightmare On Elm Street.
好了  孩子们  我们走吧
Alright children. Let's go.
谢谢少校
Thankyou Major
希望我没有吓到他们
I hope I didn't scare them too much.
我想不会的
I don't think so.
好
Good.
听着  Teyla
Ah listen, Teyla.
不要跟McKay说我认为冰球
不是男人的运动
Don't tell McKay what I said about
the hockey not being a real man's sport.
因为……他是加拿大人
他们对这件事比较敏感
Because... it's a Canadian thing, they're a little touchy about it.
我对你即将说的橄榄球更感兴趣
你说你非常喜欢这项运动
I'm interested more in hearing about his football,
you say you love so much.
我可以做的更好  跟我来
I can do one better. Come here.
爸爸  你说我们在这里能躲过幽灵吗？
Father? Do you think we are safe here,
from the Wraith?
我觉得生命中充满了不确定的东西
除了我对你的爱
I think there's nothing certain in life,
except my love for you.
你想念有风的日子么？
Do you miss the wind?
是啊  如果你非常安静的话
你可以听到海洋的声音
Yes. But if you're very quiet, you can hear the ocean.
你说那些鬼魂还住在这儿吗？
Do you think the ghosts of the ancestors still live here?
Jinto！睡觉！
Jinto! Go to sleep.
有趣
Funny.
来了  快看
Oh here it comes, watch this.
噢  真漂亮  难以置信
Oh! That is beautiful. Can you believe that?
我该不相信吗？
Should I not?
防守球员没有照顾好接球队员
因为他认为边锋不可能把球扔的这么远
Well the defence didn't cover the receiver,
cos he didn't think the quarterback could throw that far.
他们看起来很兴奋
They seem very happy.
他们刚刚排除万难  拿下了一场艰苦的比赛
Well we just won one
of the best games of all time, against all odds.
那年是Flooty赢了吧
Flooty won that year.
然后他们转战加拿大
And then went to play in Canada.
他也玩冰球吗？
He played hockey too?
嘿   你们在这儿做什么？
Hey, what are you guys doing?
告诉Teyla橄榄球是西方文明的基石
Teaching Teyla how football
is the cornerstone of Western civilization.
没叫上我？
And you didn't invite me?
你也喜欢？
You like football?
不  不喜欢
No, not really.
考虑一下吧  它很真实   不可预测
而且充满了激情和啤酒
Of course, it's real, it's unpredictable.
It's full of passion and beer.
拉拉队长
Cheerleaders.
我不明白你选择你的个人物品
你偏偏选择了这个
I just don't get that you got one personal item,
and you chose this.
这是个象征  你不觉得吗？
整个探险的过程是人类历史上最大的万福玛丽亚
It's a metaphor. Don't you see?
This entire expedition, is the biggest hail mary in human history.
什么是万福玛丽亚？
What is a hail mary?
这是你刚看过的戏的名字
用一个祷告命名的
It's a play that you just saw.
It's named after a prayer.
有个女的  她叫玛丽亚  她……
我说过我很喜欢弗累斯大转轮吗？
See this woman and her name was Mary, and she uh....
Did I mention how much I like ferris wheels?
你不想演幽灵了吗
Aren't you going to be the Wraith?
你可以演的  我演Sheppard少校
You can be the Wraith. I get to be Major Sheppard.
1,2,3,4,5,6……
One, two, three,four,five, six...
Wex？
Wex?
Jinto？
Jinto?
少校？少校！Jinto不见了
我到处找不到他
Major? Major! Jinto's missing. I can't find him.
我告诉他小心的
他碰的每一件东西都很危险
I told him to be careful,
that anything he touches can be dangerous.
如果这里有怪物怎么办？
What if there are monsters here?
我们会找到他的
We'll find him
Jinto不见了  2队听命
开始逐层搜索  从Jumpers开始  全速开动
Jinto's missing. Teams of two.
Floor to floor sweep now, starting with the Jumpers. Full gear.
遵命 长官
Yes sir!
他不在任何一个生活区里
He's not in any of the other living quarters.
我跟你一起去
I'm coming with you.
你的腿还行吗？
Are you gonna be ok with that leg?
他是我儿子
He's my son.
我们可以用感应器找到他的方位吗？
Can we use the sensors to locate him?
我们没有这么多的能量可以
来一次激活整个城市
We don't have nearly enough power
to activate the whole city at one time.
就算可以  感应器也没法分辨出……
Even if we could, the sensors don't distinguish...
人
Individuals
我们只知道  也许有些区域被屏蔽了
或者有的感应器无法正常工作
For all we know, there could be shielded areas,
or malfunctioning sensors.
在一个未爆炸的区域我们感应到
一股奇异的能量穿过城市
We are getting a pretty strange energy reading
in one of the unexplored areas, across the city.
把通讯系统激活
Activate the communication system.
好了
Done.
Jinto？我是Weir博士
如果你能听到我  请回复
Jinto? This is Doctor Weir.
If you can hear me, please respond.
Jinto？如果你丢了  如果你不能…………
Jinto? If you're lost, if you can't...
我们已经用尽能量了
We've lost power.
我们还有灯
We've still got lights.
我不知道为什么会这样
I don't know why that happened.
不是我干的
That wasn't me!
把它关了
Shut it down now!
- 这到底是怎么了
- 我不知道
- What the hell is going on?
- I don't know.
- 这种情况从未发生过
- 我们到这儿才几天
- Nothing like this has happened before.
- We've only been here for a couple of days.
这些设备都很老了
或许真的有鬼魂
This stuff is pretty old. It's that, or there really are ghosts.
控制室吗 我是Sheppard  灯突然熄灭了
Control room, this is Sheppard. The lights just went out.
少校  我们碰到一些机械故障
Major, we're experiencing some technical malfunctions
我想应该跟发生器和城市之间的接口有关
I think it's something to do with the interfaces
between our naquada generators and the city.
我们隔离某些系统的方法可能会
导致古代程序的错误操作
That, or the way we isolated certain systems,
could be causing erroneous operations in the Ancient programming.
我来诊断一下功率通量
I'll run a diagnostic on the power flow.
我没想到你还信鬼神
I wouldn't have thought you believed in ghosts.
以前可不是的  自从我见到幽灵以后
他们可以用手把灵魂吸出来  那到底是怎么回事
I never used to. Then I learned about things called Wraiths,
that can suck the life out of you with their hands. What the hell is that?
Weir博士？
Dr Weir?
Teyla  我会尽快赶到  你先控制局面
Teyla, I'll be right there. Do what you can.
好的
Right.
Weir博士 我是Marta
Dr Weir, this is Marta.
很高兴见到你
Pleased to meet you.
没事的  告诉她你看到什么
It's alright. Tell her what you saw.
一个阴影
A shadow.
那是幽灵搞的鬼
让你看到幻境
The Wraith project them.
Make you see things that aren't there.
你确定？
Are you sure?
我还没感觉到幽灵
And yet I sense no Wraith here.
Teyla你是不是有感觉错误的时候
Sheppard少校  我是Weir
Teyla, have you ever been wrong about that?
Major Sheppard? This is Weir.
有一个Ethosian人说她看到一个
阴影状的东西
One of the Ethosians is claiming to have seen,
what she's calling a shadow.
她不相信我？
She does not believe me?
Teyla说她没感觉到附近有幽灵
但我仍感到怀疑
Teyla say's that she senses no Wraith here,
but I'm still concerned.
好吧  我会后退到控制室
你们等下一个命令
Alright, I'll just fall back to the gateroom,
and wait for further instructions.
我们不能停止搜索
We can't stop searching.
如果这里有危险的话
我们需要建立防御工事
If there is a threat here, we need to establish a proper perimeter.
我已经确保了控制塔和生活区的进出安全
I've secured access to the control tower and the living quarters.
又有两个Ethosian人报告说看到阴影
Two more Ethosians reported seeing the shadows.
我弄不明白
如果真是这样的话  那意味着幽灵已经在这儿了
You know, I don't get that.
That means the Wraith would be here.
你不认为吗？
You don't think so?
我认为他们没必要吓唬我们
他们决定要来的话  直接开着飞船就来了
I don't think they wanna scare us. When they decide to come?
They're gonna start blowing the crap out of this place with their ships.
那又如何？Ethosian人只是看到了一些东西？
So what? The Ethosians are just seeing things?
就算Teyla说的那样  他们在这里感到恐惧吧
Well, like Teyla said, it's a scary place for them.
不单对他们
Not just for them.
Hollan想跟Jinto说话
Hollan wishes to speak with Jinto.
请
Please.
来吧
Go ahead.
Jinto！如果你能听到我  我告诉你我不生气
我只是想知道你现在是安全的
Jinto! If you can hear me, I'm not angry.
I just want to know that you are safe.
如果你迷路或者受伤了  呆在原地别动
可能的话弄出点声音 我们会找到你的
So if you are lost, or hurt, stay where you are.
Make some noise if you can. We will find you.
他说的是拉丁语吗？
Is that Latin?
是古语  永恒圣殿的光之父？
It's Ancient. Fathers of the light, of the everlasting temple?
这个祭祖的祷告语
It is a prayer to the ancestors.
如果你对我们不恰当的定居在这个城市感到生气的话
我们表示诚挚的道歉
If you are angry that we have unrightfully inhabited your great city,
we humbly apologise.
我们没有恶意  如果这是你的旨意
我们会离开的  但没有儿子我是不会走的
We mean no harm. We will leave, if it is your wish.
But I will not go without my son.
- 他晕过去了
- 能用个好点的词吗
- He fainted.
- There's gotta be a better word.
“晕”是最恰当的医学用语
Faint, is the proper medical term.
我由于饥饿昏倒了
I passed out from manly hunger.
你在这等一下
Well, hang in there
Weir博士？McKay没事了
他晕倒了
Dr Weir? McKay is ok. He fainted.
是的  很有同情心嘛
我们一起来嘲笑这个要死的人吧  谢谢
Oh yes. Very sympathetic.
Let's all mock the dying man. Thankyou.
这不像是幽灵使你看到的那种幻象
It didn't look like the phantoms
the Wraith's make you see,
现在我知道Ethosian人为什么感到迷惑了
but I can see how the Ethosians
would be confused.
- 它看起来什么样？
- 就像………………
- What did it look like?
- It looked like a....
黑暗
Darkness.
它环绕着发生器  然后开始膨胀
It surrounded the naquadah generator
and started to grow.
就像在吸取能量一样
Like it was feeding off the energy.
把发生器关了以后   整个
不管它是什么玩意儿了  它就不见了
When you shut it down, the whole,
whatever it was, it just went away.
如果这东西吸取能量的话
我们的麻烦就大了
If this thing feeds on energy,
we could be in big trouble.
我刚才说“我们”  其实我指的是“你们”
因为我撑不了那么久了
And when I say we, I mean you, because
I won't actually be around for much longer.
我们必须弄清这到底是什么东西
是用来做什么的
So we need to figure out exactly
what it is and what to do about it.
- 我知道它对能量感兴趣
- 关掉发生器怎么样？
- We know it's attracted to energy.
- How about shutting down the generators.
人也会散发热量
Well people also give off heat energy.
显然这个发生器产生的热量
不是一个数量级的
Granted it's negligible compared to
that of a naquadah generator,
但只有你吃过东西以后……
but you take away this things
only other obvious sort of food and....
你是说它会跟着我们吗？
Are you saying it could come after us?
只有一件事我是肯定的
我们生活在飞翔的黑暗中
Well I only know one thing for sure,
and that is flying darkness
这会极大极大的消耗能量
that eats energy,
can only be very, very bad.
好吧  我们把电源开着
Groden  尽快找到侦测阴影的方法
Ok, we keep the power on.
Groden, figure out a way to detect it,
同时少校负责对所有的发生器进行监督
and Major, in the meantime, establish
a constant surveillance on all the generators.
如果其中有一个被盯上来
我们就把它关了
If one of them is targeted,
we'll shut it down remotely.
这样或许可以使阴影疲于奔命
And hopefully we can keep this thing busy,
我们就有时间找到摆脱它的办法
until we figure out a way to get rid of it.
所有人注意  我是Weir
Attention everyone, this is Weir!
从现在开始  我要求你们停在原地
除非另有通知  如果你们看见……
For the time being, we need you all to remain in your quarters,
unless otherwise instructed. If you see anything out of the....
Hello！你能听到我说话吗？
有人能听到我说话吗？
Hello! Can you hear me? Can anyone hear me?
Jinto？
Jinto?
Sheppard少校！
Major Sheppard!
你还好吗？
Are you ok?
我很害怕
I'm scared.
你在哪儿？
Where are you?
我不知道
I don't know.
Jinto  从头开始说
告诉我们你怎么到那儿的
Jinto start from the beginning.
Tell us how you got to where you are.
我在走廊上  在我的生活区外面
I was in the hall, outside my quarters.
然后呢？
Where did you go next?
我记不起来了
I can't remember.
他习惯丛林生活  可以在晚上辨识星星
He's used to the forest. Being able to see the stars at night.
我发现了一个小屋
里面装满了地球上来的盒子
I found a small room, filled with boxes from Earth.
盒子不见了
No boxes.
它们在我这儿
They are here with me.
这里用来做壁橱不错
This room would make a nice closet.
这一定不是壁橱
是不是你进来以后那个面板就开始发热了呢？
This is definitely not a closet.
Did the panel start to glow, when you stepped inside?
是啊
Yes.
你碰了它吗？
Did you touch it?
是啊
Yes
怎么碰的？
What exactly?
记不起来了
I don't remember
在他消失之前  我们收到一个来自这个
区域的反常的能量信号
Just before he disappeared, we got
an unusual energy reading from this area here.
哦  不  不
Oh, no, no.
- 一定是个运输机
- 现在还不急着给它起名字
- Must be a transporter.
- We can name it later.
Sheppard少校
Major Sheppard.
Jinto  你还好吗？
Jinto, are you ok?
- 好的
-  我已经找到Jinto了  他很好
- Yes
- I've got Jinto, and he's ok.
你知道这是什么地方吗？
Do you have any idea, what this place is?
是个实验室之类的东西
我们以前见过一些
Some sort of research lab.
We've come across a few of them.
这些控制台通常用来登录
中央计算系统
These consoles generally access
the central computer system,
所以Jinto可能在这里触发了刚才
我们以为的故障
so Jinto could have cause what
we thought were malfunctions, from here.
我必须知道你都碰了些什么东西
Look, I need to know,
everything you touched.
从我目前的调查来看  应该只有一个物体
As far as I can tell, there's only one entity.
蓝色的亮点是活动者的发生器
The bright blue spots
are the active naquadah generators.
这个斑点是那个东西
只是感应器的校准问题
This blob is our entity.
It was just a matter of calibrating the sensors.
你的主意很有用
到目前为止我都是占先的
Your idea's working.
So far I've been able to anticipate
当它靠近活动的发生器时
我就遥控把发生器关掉
it's approach to the active generators,
and shut them off remotely.
这儿  看
Here, watch.
-  它现在只能团团转
- 干的好
- Got it going in circles.
- Good job.
谢谢
Thanks.
我希望我们没有使这东西发疯
I hope we're not making this thing mad.
中尉？我是Groden博士
我侦测到那个物体向你那个方向前进
Lt? This is Doctor Groden.
I'm tracking the entity going your way.
你最好不要站在走廊上
进到一个屋子里
You might want to get out of the hallway,
you're standing in.
收到
Roger that!
我是Ford
一道舱门挡住我我们的去路
This is Ford.
A bulkhead just blocked our way.
门上没有面板
也没看见可以开门的东西
There's no panel on the wall,
or any way to open it that we can see.
-  收到
-  McKay？
- Roger that.
- McKay?
我们没有碰任何东西  可能是那个东西
导致了随机产生的故障
We didn't touch anything. It could be
the entity, causing random malfuntions.
有这个大的一个东西干扰  这些古代的科技
很可能会出故障的
Proximity to that large an entity disturbance, could
cause the Ancient technology to go haywire.
中校  往回跑
试试走廊东侧的那道门
Lt double back and try the door
on the east side of the hall.
- 这扇门也打不开
- 它来了
- This door won't open, either.
- Here it comes.
打开墙上的控制台
Open the console on the wall.
快
Hurry!
-  接下来呢
-  我不清楚  你看到什么？
- What next?
- I'm not sure. What do you see?
- 3个水晶
- 取出中间一个  把上面那个往下推
- Three crystals.
- Take out the middle one, pull the top one down.
如果门开的话  快跑
If this door opens, go.
我会跟在你后面
I'll be right behind you.
没用
It's not working.
用中间那个把其他两个连接上
Ok, use the middle one to bridge the two others.
-  你确定吗？
- 不确定
- You sure about this?
- Not exactly.
跑！
Go!
派人下来  这里需要医疗
Man down, I need a medical team.
好的  你们别动
Right, hang in there.
- 我们这儿是不是有危险？
- 我希望我能告诉你
- Are we in any danger here?
- I wish I could tell you.
- Ford怎么了？
- 他就像被闪电击中了一样
- How's Ford?
- It's like he was hit by lightening.
- 他会没事吗？
- 他很强壮的
- He's gonna be ok?
- He's a tough kid.
长官
Sir.
Hi
Hi.
你可以跟他说
其实他没有责任吗？
Will you tell this guy,
there's nothing he could have done?
你没有责任
There is nothing you could have done.
我本可以把他拉出来的  长官
I could have tried to pull him out sir.
那我们就一起躺在床上了
Then we'd both look like this.
哦  你看起来还不是很糟
Ah, you don't look so bad.
Beckett博士说你很快就会恢复原样了
Dr Beckett says you're gonna
be back to pretty boy, in no time.
-  显然这也是一个升降舵
- 真的？
- Apparently it's also an elevator.
- Really?
你可以不用带着楼梯到处跑了
You can stop taking the stairs everywhere.
- 你们真是好人
- 你发现了什么吗？
- Oh, how nice for you all.
- What have you got?
信不信由你  Jinto没有动其他东西导致不良结果
除了那个
Well believe it or not, Jinto didn't touch
anything of any consequence, other than that.
他一定有自己的能量源
就像“跳跃者”一样
It must have it's own power source,
like the Jumpers.
这是什么？
What is it?
这有点像核反应堆的安全壳
提供能源的
Well it's some sort of containment vessel,
for the energy creature.
Jinto释放了它？
And Jinto released it?
看起来是这样的
而且据我看
Well, it seems that way.
As I suggested,
这些能量就是导致技术问题的根源
the energies must be causing
most of the technical problems.
它会被观测捕捉到
It was captured for observation.
古代人正研究升天技术
The Ancients were researching ascension.
- 真的？
- 什么是升天技术？
- Really?
- What exactly is ascension?
在他们进化的某个阶段
古代人到达了
Well at some point during their evolution,
the Ancients reached a...
一个更高的境界  他们可以脱离
他们的躯壳
an advanced stage of being, where they were able
to rid themselves of their physical bodies,
升到一个更高的地方
并以纯能量的形式存在着
and rise to a higher plane of existence.
One in which they live as pure energy.
我知道听起来有些荒谬
但这是第一个线索
I know it sounds ridiculous,
but this is the first indication
可能有一种力量阻挠了这种进化
that there may have been evolutionary
intervention to get there.
是他们的基因治疗吗？
A little gene therapy of their own huh?
呃  我还没读过所有的笔记
但我知道那个怪物是个能量体
Well I haven't read all the notes, but
what I do know, is that the entity is energy.
它靠能量存活  Ford很幸运
我是说  它吃得越多 体积会变得越大
It feeds on energy. Fords lucky, I mean,
the more it feeds, the bigger it gets.
它变得越大  就会吸收更多的能量
这样会更致命
The bigger it gets, the more charged it becomes.
The more deadly it will be.
它是智能的吗？
Is it intelligent?
根据研究结果
它是有意识的
Well according to the research,
it is sentient.
但如果你想和它说话
那估计比和一只大白鲨说话还难
But if you tried to talk to it, you'd have
more luck with a great white shark.
这个东西会把发生器的所有能量吸走
那样我们就都完蛋了
This thing is going to suck the power out
of our generators, and then it will kill us all.
好的  那我们该怎么做
Alright, what will we do about it?
自从古代人丢弃了这个城市开始
那个东西就一直被困在这儿了
The entity's been trapped in here, since before
the Ancient's abandoned the city.
-  我知道我会生气的
- 而且很饿
- I know I'd be pissed.
- And hungry.
重点是  这个设备是设计来
The point is,
this device was designed to track it,
跟踪  捕捉它的
capture it, and hold it for observation.
我们仍然有机会把它赶回去
There's still a chance we may be able to get it back inside.
我需要再多一些时间来找到方法
I'm just gonna need a little more time to figure how.
- Hello
- Jinto有话要说
- Jinto has something he wishes to say.
对不起  都是我的错
I'm sorry. What happened to you was my fault.
我的家乡有句俗话
Where I come from, we've got a little saying.
是福不是祸  是祸躲不过
Stuff happens.
这次情况有些不同
但你不是有意的  是吗？
It's a little different, but you didn't mean
for this to happen, did you?
嗯  你是个好孩子
No. You're a good kid.
你没有做错事
你也没有什么错  OK？
You weren't doing anything wrong,
which means this isn't your fault, ok?
就像我们到你们的星球一样
Same as when we came to your planet?
我们不希望幽灵出现
但他们就是出现了
We didn't mean for the Wraith to show up,
they just did.
这也是你在这儿的原因
你的家没了
That's why you're here.
Your home was destroyed.
你还差点失去父亲
我记得你不曾为了这件事对我生气
You almost lost your dad. I don't
remember you getting mad with me over that.
是福不是祸  是祸躲不过
Stuff happens.
它不再中计了
It's not falling for the same tricks anymore.
- 它有多聪明？
- Rodney？
- How smart is this thing?
- Rodney?
我不知道
但这比我想的要简单
I don't know.
But this is much simpler than I thought.
就像一个捕鼠器
It's kind of like a mousetrap.
这里的按钮使设备发射出能量信号
吸引那个东西
This button here, causes the device to emit
an energy signature that attracts the creature.
这里  则是关掉能量信号的
This one, shuts it in.
现在只有往下走
Now the only downside, is it looks like
看起来好像得有人在这里按着这按钮
someone's actually gonna have
to be here to press the buttons.
- 我来
- 好的
- I'll do it.
- Ok
等一下  Rodney
你还带着保护层
Wait a minute Rodney.
You're still wearing the shield.
是不是意味着如果发生意外的话
它会保护你？
Is there a chance that if something went wrong,
that would protect you?
我有预感
I had a feeling.
你说什么
预感什么？
What do you mean?
Had a feeling about what?
你是说我刚才想着让它脱落吗？
You think I wanted to come off just now?
你认为我害怕了吗？
我才不怕呢  让我来
You think I'm scared?
I'm not scared, I'll do this.
不  没关系
你可能会再晕过去
No that's ok.
You might faint again.
不  这个不起作用了
Look, it's just not working anymore. Look,
它在你身上也不起作用
it doesn't work on you either.
我只是不想让你去死
I just meant that I wasn't going to let you die.
这只是一个巧合  它刚好失效了
我要喝水！
It's just a coincidence that it happened
to stop working now. I need a drink!
走
Go.
你一直告诉我
我不该害怕黑暗
You always told me,
I shouldn't be afraid of the dark.
我错了
Well, I was wrong.
我现在睡不着
I can't sleep now.
如果黑暗来临怎么办？
What if the darkness comes?
不会的
It won't.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
因为
Because.
它害怕火光
It's afraid of fire.
黑暗害怕了？
The darkness is afraid?
所谓一物降一物
Everything is afraid of something.
那个保护层自己脱落了
So the shield device,
just came off by itself.
是啊  正巧失效了
Yeah. It just stopped working.
他还在Sheppard身上试了试
He even tried it on Sheppard.
在Sheppard身上是无效的
It wouldn't work on Sheppard.
为什么？
Why not?
McKay没跟你说吗？
文献上说  保护层在佩戴者身上留下烙印
McKay didn't tell you? The text we studied,
said the shield imprints on the wearer
如果我们没搞错的话  它对其他人是无效的
If we were right, it wouldn't work on anyone else
准备好了吗？
We're ready?
你应该清楚如果我们把所有设备关掉
我们将失去传感器
You do realise that when we shut everything
down, we're going to lose the sensors.
我们就没法对它定位了
We're not going to be able to track it.
我们派了安保人员
在生活区四处巡逻
We have security personnel,
posted around the living quarters.
至少我们有个警报系统
At least we have some warning.
Teyla告诉一个Ethosian孩子
点亮的蜡烛会保护他们
Teyla told the Ethosian children, that lighting
a candle will help protect them.
- 你这么做是因为……
- 这里会变黑
- And you're doing it because....
- It's gonna get dark in here.
好了  少校  开始吧
Ok Major. Go ahead.
现在
Now.
关掉电源
Shutting down power.
他来了
It's coming.
我想我们需要一艘更大的船
I think we're gonna need a bigger boat.
- 大小没关系
- 真是个神话
- Size doesn't matter.
- That's a myth.
它会进得去
那个设备会把它吸进去
It'll fit. The device traps the creature inside.
你只要保证它进到那个安全壳里就行了
You just need to make sure, it's all
the way inside the containment vessel
好的  来吧
Alright, come on.
该死的
Son of a bitch.
怎么了？
What happened?
那个东西看了一眼   然后走了
The damn thing took one look and went away.
它比我想象的聪明多了
It's a lot smarter than we thought.
我们需要知道到哪儿了  现在
We need to know where it is, right now.
我们必须打开开关  打开传感器
We'll have to turn the power on, to use the sensors.
- 你不能这样做
- 就这样做  只开启控制塔
- You can't do that.
- Do it, just the operations tower.
现在怎么了？
What now?
- 它朝着这个方向去了
- 因为你有打开了开关
- It's headed this way.
- Because you turned the power back on.
我们不能再这样下去了
We can't go on like this.
你们认为它想呆在这儿吗？
Do you think it wants to be here?
什么意思？
What do you mean?
它被困在这儿已有千年  孑然一身
It's been trapped here for thousands of years, alone.
这里不再寂寞了呀
It's not alone anymore.
它的思维没有到这个高度
它只会想吃的 仅此而已
It doesn't think on that level.
It thinks about eating, that's it.
- 你知道什么
- 如果我们呆在这儿  它会杀了我们
- You would know.
- If we stay, it will kill us.
-  除非我们先把它杀了
- 可是我看不到杀它的希望
- Not unless we kill it first.
- Well, I don't see how.
也就是说不是我们走就是它走
Then either we must go, or it must.
也许它想离开
Maybe it wants to go.
如果我们打开星际门
If we open the Stargate.
这主意真烂
This is a bad idea.
- 你说过好多遍了
- 可是这值得说上一万遍
- You've said that already.
- Well, it's worth saying again.
它来了！
It's coming!
打开的星际门是一个巨大的能量源
它真聪明
An open stargate, is a huge power source.
This thing is smart.
它足够聪明  不会再被困在一个安全壳里了
It knew enough, not to get trapped
in the containment vessel again.
那你凭什么认为它会随着一个发生器进入虫洞里呢？
What makes you think it's going to follow
a naquadah generator through a wormhole?
什么  你有更好的主意吗？
What, you got a better idea?
好运！
Good luck!
你行吗？
Are you ok?
它快来了
It's almost here.
- 你们有地址吗？
- M4X 337  贫瘠的荒地
- Do you have an address?
- M4X 337, barren wasteland
接通
Dial it.
想法不错
That was good thinking.
它没有进去
It's not going anywhere.
我们看不见它是否进去了
We can't see if the malp got through.
那个东西可能会耗尽电池
The entity could have drained the battery.
它可能会吸收星际门以及发生器的能量
那样就糟了
It could be feeding off the stargate,
off the generator. This is a disaster.
关掉
Shut it down.
- 关不掉
- 控制台失效了
- I can't.
- The consoles are dead.
一定还有挽救的措施
There must be something we can do.
我们不知道它是否还在那儿
We don't know if the malp is still down there.
也许那个东西还是会穿过星际门
It's possible that the entity will still go through the gate,
一旦它耗尽了发生器的能量的话
once it's depleted the energy
in the naquadah generator, on the malp.
或者它会吸掉星际门的能量
Or it could just continue to feed off the gates energy.
McKay！
McKay!
Rodney！
Rodney!
Mckay？
McKay?
能量一定都被那个东西耗尽了
The power must have been drained by the entity.
医疗队马上到门厅来
Medical team to the gateroom.
他没有被灼伤  他有呼吸
He's not burned. He's breathing.
McKay？
McKay?
McKay
- 怎么了？
- 你成功了
- What append?
- you did it.
成功了？
I did?
它穿过那扇门了
It went through the gate.
你一定死过一回了
You must have passed out.
谢谢你们没说什么别的
Well thanks for not saying the other thing.
这真是个万福玛丽亚
That, was a Hail Mary.
谢谢  不急
我没事
Thankyou, take your time.
Man down.